Guide to the Fred Eggan Papers 1870-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series VI: North American Indian Files
  - Subseries 14: Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute
    - All-Pueblo Council, minutes, Santo Domingo Pueblo, manuscript, March 15, 1934 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on Land Problems in the Pueblo Southwest, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1975-1976 (Box 95, Folder 8-9)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, manuscripts, correspondence, newsletter, 1983-1984 (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, correspondence, 1985 (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, manuscripts, correspondence, newsletter, 1986 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, manuscripts, correspondence, 1987 (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - American Anthropological Association, Panel on the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, report, correspondence, 1988 (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - American Anthropological Association, Plenary Session on North American Indian Studies, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, Cincinnati, November 29, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - American Anthropological Association, "Resolution on Hopi-Navajo Relocation, " manuscript, 1981 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - American Anthropological Association, Wilcomb E. Washburn, "Anthropological Advocacy in the Hopi-Navajo Land Dispute, " manuscript, correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Arnold and Porter, legal counsel, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1986-1990 (Box 96, Folder 4-5)
    - Bean, Stanley and Dale Metzger, Antioch College, "The Indian Land Claim, " flyer, 1956 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, correspondence, 1964, 1970 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, manuscript, correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, staff conference, August 12-13, 1982 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, "Hopi-1934 Reservation Case, " maps, 1983 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, transcript of direct examination of Fred Eggan in Healing v Jones, Prescott Trial, 1960, correspondence, 1983 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, staff conference, November 26-27, 1984 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, indexes to court documents and exhibits, undated (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Boyden, Kennedy, Romney and Howard, Law Offices, correspondence, 1977 (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Boyden, Tibbals, Staten and Croft, Law Offices, manuscripts, correspondence, 1955-1963 (Box 96, Folder 15-16)
    - Brugge, David, manuscript, correspondence, reprint, 1965-1968 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - The Final Report, " manuscript, 1967 (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - Colton, Harold S., "History of the Hopi Indians from Archaeological Evidence, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1962 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Diehl, H.C., manuscripts, correspondence, 1942-1961 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Euler, Robert C., manuscripts, correspondence, reprints, 1978-1989 (Box 97, Folder 3-5)
    - Fowler, Don D., Hopi comparative philology, correspondence, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities, correspondence, 1989 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Godfrey, Anthony, "Preliminary Hopi Agricultural Report, " manuscript, April, 1984 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Greenway, John, reprints, correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Hasgood, Eugene, "Diné Evictees of District Six, " manuscripts, undated (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Hopi, plaintiff's exhibits, dockets 196 and 198, maps, undated (Box A)
    - Hopi archaeology, manuscripts, 1937-1961 (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - Hopi archaeological surveys, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1960-1961 (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - Hopi Constitution, 1936-1946, correspondence, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Hopi meeting, Hotevilla, Arizona, transcript, April 25, 1955 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Hopi Message, newsletter, August 7, 1961 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - Hopi Moencopi settlement, manuscripts, reprints, 1983 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Hopi Tribe, Ivan L. Sidney, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer, correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Jenkins, Sam, correspondence, 1965 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Johnson, Fred A., correspondence, 1964 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Kennedy and Pugsley, Attorneys at Law, correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy and Romney, Attorneys at Law, Hopi1934 Case Experts' Conference, 1985 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Levy, Jerry, correspondence, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - McFeat, Tom F. S., correspondence, 1961 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Mekeel, H.S., correspondence, 1936 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Nagata, Shuichi, correspondence, 1981 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Navajo Times, newspapers, 1964 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Navajo Tribal Council, minutes, March 12-13, 1934 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Navajo exhibits, docket 229, notes, undated (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Nielsen and Senior, Attorneys and Counselors, correspondence, 1984 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Orans, Martin, correspondence, 1990 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Pandey, Triloki Nath, correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Quinn, William W., notes, reprint, 1983 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Schaafsma, C.F., notes, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - Schoolcraft, H. R., manuscript, notes, undated (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Schroeder, Albert H., Defendant's Exhibits, docket 229 maps, bibliography for maps, correspondence, 1961 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Smith, A. Watson, Hopi bibliography, 1950 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Sonosky, Chambers and Sachse, Law Offices, correspondence, 1986 (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - U.S., Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, Henry M. Jackson, Chairman, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, 1973-1974 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - U.S., Healing v. Jones, Supreme Court, documents, 1962 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - U.S., Healing v. Jones, District Court, Arizona, Defendants exhibits 230b, National Archives, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Record Group 75, Central Classified File 24705-40-304.3, photocopies, undated (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - U.S., Healing v. Jones, District Court, pretrial order No. 2, 1962 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - U.S., Jones v. Healing, Supreme Court, documents, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - U.S., National Archives, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Record Group 75, Central Classified File 24705-40-304.3, Hopi-Navajo Boundary Report, photocopies (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - U.S., National Park Service, Southwest Region, manuscripts, correspondence, 1967 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - U.S., Navajo and Hopi Land Exchange Amendments Act, 99th Cong., 1st Sess, 1985 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - U.S., Navajo and Hopi Relocation Commission, reports, correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - U.S., Navajo and Hopi Relocation Commission, Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation, correspondence, 1991 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - U.S., Office of Indian Affairs, correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - U.S., Sekaquaptewa v. MacDonald, District Court, Arizona, April 5, 1978, 448 Federal Supplement 1183, No. Civ. 74-842 Pct. WPC (Box 99, Folder 8)
    - U.S., Sekaquaptewa v. MacDonald, Court of Appeals, Ninth Circuit, May 23, 1980, 619 Federal Reporter, 2d Series 801, Nos. 78-3504, 78-3505 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - U.S., Sidney v. MacDonald, District Court, Arizona, depostition of Fred Eggan, 1988 (Box 99, Folder 10-12)
    - U.S., Sidney v. Zah, District Court, Arizona, subpoena, schedule of documents, 1983 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - U.S., Statistical Summary, Human Dependency Survey, Navajo and Hopi Reservations, 1939 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - U.S., Statistical Summary, Human Dependency Survey, Navajo Reservation and Grazing District 7, 1941 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - U.S., Statutes at Large 48 Stat. 960, June 14, 1934, An Act to define the exterior boundaries of the Navajo Indian Reservation in Arizona, and for other purposes, 1934 (Box 99, Folder 16)
    - U.S., Statutes at Large 88 Public Law 93-531December 22, 1974(1974), pp. 1712-1713, Determination of tribal rights and interests in land--Authorization to commence and defend actions in District Court, 1974 (Box 99, Folder 17)
    - U.S., Wheeler-Howard Indian Rights Bill, H. R. 7902, 73d Cong., 2d Sess., 1934 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - University of Chicago, Social Science Research Committee, correspondence, 1942 (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Waters, Frank, Book of the Hopi, correspondence, book reviews, 1964 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, correspondence, 1986 (Box 99, Folder 21)
    - Whiteley, Peter, correspondence, 1984 (Box 99, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, clippings, photocopies, 1940-1986 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified correspondence, 1942, 1986 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 15: Zuni Land Claims
    - Sub-subseries 1: Research Material
      - Notes, undated (Box 100, Folder 3-5)
      - Notes, overview of case, undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
      - Notes, trial schedule, 1982 (Box 100, Folder 7)
      - Notes, Zuni ethno-ornithology, undated (Box 100, Folder 8)
      - Notes, Zuni social, mythical and religious systems, undated (Box 100, Folder 9)
      - "Aboriginal Land Use of the Zuni Indian Tribe, " manuscript, undated (Box 100, Folder 10)
      - Aboriginal Land Use of the Zuni Indian Tribe, " manuscript, undated (Box 100, Folder 11)
      - "Kinship System of the Zuni Indians, " student paper, 1932 (Box 100, Folder 12)
      - "Zuni History, 1850-1970, " with T. N. Pandey, galley proof, undated (Box 100, Folder 13)
      - Bartlett, Katharine, "The Distribution of the Indians of Arizona in 1848, " reprint, correspondence, 1945, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 14)
      - Some Interpretations from Central Western New Mexico, " photocopy, 1968 (Box 100, Folder 15)
      - A Summary of Zuni Tribal History A.D. 1450-1700, " manuscript, correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 100, Folder 16)
      - Fritz, John M., correspondence, Greg McHolm, "Zuni Classificatory Systems in Relation to Prehistoric Social Change in Arizona, " manuscript, 1970 (Box 100, Folder 17)
      - Hart, Richard, correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 100, Folder 18)
      - Ladd, Edmund J., "Pueblo Uses of High Altitude Areas--Emphasis on the A:shiwi-Zuni, " manuscript, undated (Box 100, Folder 19)
      - Perspectives on Society, Land Use and Technology, table of contents, notes, correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 100, Folder 20)
      - Lewis, Robert E., Certificate of Appreciation to Fred Eggan, correspondence, 1990 (Box 100, Folder 21)
      - Morris, Elizabeth A., "High Altitude Sites in the Mogollon Rim Area of Arizona and New Mexico, " manuscript, correspondence, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 22)
      - Navajo, clippings, publications, 1968-1985 (Box 100, Folder 23)
      - Newman, Stanley, Zuni linguistics, reprint, copies, 1964-1965 (Box 100, Folder 24)
      - Pandey, Triloki Nath, "Land Problems among the Zuni Indian, " manuscript, correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - Plog, Fred, photocopies, correspondence, 1980 (Box 101, Folder 2)
      - Experiences and Descriptions, " "A Glossary of Common Zuni Terms, " photocopies, 1973 (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - An Ethnohistorical Report, " manuscript, 1974 (Box 101, Folder 4-5)
      - Roberts, John M., "Zuni Bibliography, " manuscript, correspondence, 1956-1980 (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - A Review, " manuscript, correspondence, 1981 (Box 101, Folder 7)
      - Schaafsma, Curtis F., "Statement Read by Curtis F. Schaafsma at the Presidential Task Force Hearing on the American Indian Religious Freedom Act at Zuni Pueblo onJune 23, 1979," manuscript, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 8)
      - Schroeder, Albert H., correspondence, 1980 (Box 101, Folder 9)
      - Stevenson, Mathilda Coxe, Zuni ethnobotany, photocopies, 1912 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      - Zuni History, newspaper, 1983 (Box 101, Folder 11)
      - Victories in the 1990s, newspaper, correspondence, 1991 (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - Zuni History Conference, notes, program, September 11, 1982 (Box 101, Folder 13)
      - Unidentified, correspondence, undated (Box 101, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous, clippings, photocopies, manuscripts, 1891-1979 (Box 101, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1951-1964 (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Zuni Indian Tribe of New Mexico v. The United States of America
      - "Position of Earl H. Elam, Ph.D., " copy, 1980-1981 (Box 101, Folder 17)
      - Dr. Earl H. Elam..., " by Fred Eggan and T. J. Ferguson, copy, notes, 1980-1981 (Box 101, Folder 18)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, correspondence, typescripts, 1976-1979 (Box 102, Folder 1)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, "Aboriginal Land Use of the Zuni Indian Tribe, " manuscript, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 2)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, Law Offices, court documents, notes, typescript, 1980-1985 (Box 102, Folder 3-4)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, expenses, notes, correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 102, Folder 5)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, trial conference, March 28-29, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 6)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, trial conference, August 11, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 7)
      - Boyden, Kennedy and Romney, trial conference, January 30-31, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 8)
      - Defendant's exhibits, (Docket No. 161-79 L), photocopies, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 9-10)
      - Defendant's Supplemental Reports, source nos. 1-26, photocopies, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 11)
      - Examination and cross examination of Fred Eggan, transcript of questions, 1982 (Box 102, Folder 12)
- Series VII: Philippines Files
  This series spans the years 1904 to 1986, and contains field notes, correspondence, manuscripts, student papers, dissertations, research proposals, bibliographies, whole Philippine newspapers, and other media clippings, reports, travel diaries, and photographs. The files are arranged into 13 subseries with general topics such as linguistics, politics, social science research, and also by named cultural identity or tribe. The nucleus of the series is a large amount of field data collected by Eggan and many others concerning peoples of the northern Philippines. Specifically, these field data include maps, climate and language charts, kinship diagrams and genealogies, myth, folktale, and song texts, grammars, and descriptions of rituals. Many of Fay-Cooper Cole's original field notes from 1907-1908 are preserved here as well. Eggan established long-term connections with colleagues and informants in the Philippines who supplied him with ethnographic information in a variety of forms--correspondence, field notes, manuscripts, and diaries. Among the Ilongot materials is a considerable body of ethnographic and linguistic data originally compiled by ethnologist William Jones in 1908-1909. Eggan's own field notes concerning the northern Philippines are located in the sections on Bontoc, Nabaloi, Tinguian, Town Field Notes and Photographs, and Sagada. The final section of the Philippines Files series contains the findings of the American Anthropological Associations' special panel on the "Tasaday Controversy" chaired by Eggan in 1989. The controversy involved debate concerning the extent to which the Tasaday had lived in isolation and technological primitiveness prior to their "discovery" by Westerners in 1971. Series VII: Philippines Files
  - Subseries 1: Linguistics
    - A Preliminary Appraisal of the North American Data, " manuscripts, correspondence, reprints, 1955-1957 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Linguistic worksheets, undated (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Beyer, H. Otley, "List of Philippine Languages and Dialects, " manuscript, ca.1942 (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Brandstetter, Renward, Malayo-Polynasische Forschungen II. Tagalen und Madagassen, reprint, 1902 (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Conklin, Harold C., "Outline Gazetteer of Native Philippine Ethnic and Linguistic Groups, " manuscript, correspondence, 1952 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Conklin, Harold C., "Test Vocabulary for Philippine Languages, "1953 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Costenoble, H., notes, reprints, 1973 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Dempwolff, Otto, "An English Translation of Dempwolff's Word List, "undated (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Dyen, Isidore, "Subgrouping Philippine Languages, " manuscript, undated (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Fox, Robert B., linguistic chart, undated (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Fox, Robert B., "Lexical Check List of a Dialect Spoken Pampanga, "undated (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Fox, Robert B., "A Special Note on the Negros-Bisayan Syllabary Recorded by Povedano, " manuscript, syllabary, undated (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Guemple, D. L., "Malayo-Polynesian Phonemic Systems, " manuscript, undated (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Guemple, D. L., "Preliminary Glottochronology for Central Philippines, " student paper, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - Hamp, Eric, Philippine phonemic systems, notes, undated (Box 103, Folder 15)
    - Reid, Lawrence A., correspondence, 1984 (Box 103, Folder 16)
    - Yamada, Yukihiro, "A Preliminary Itbayaten Vocabulary, " manuscript, 1966 (Box 103, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1946-1980 (Box 103, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2: Politics
    - "The Philippines and the Bell Report, " reprint, 1951 (Box 103, Folder 19)
    - Foreign aid, clippings, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 20)
    - Formal Philippine structure and its relation to the political units, diagram, undated (Box 103, Folder 21)
    - A Study of the Relationship of Political Culture to Political Modernization, " dissertation proposal, undated (Box 103, Folder 22)
    - Hester, E. D., United States-Philippine relations, memorandum, 1953 (Box 103, Folder 23)
    - Marcos, Ferdinand E., address to the United States House of Representatives, Congressional Record, September 15, 1966 (Box 103, Folder 24)
    - National elections, Novemeber, 10, 1953, manuscripts, reprints, 1946-1954 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Philippine social commentary, manuscripts, undated (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Rahmann, Rudolf, "Our Responsibilities towards the Cultural Minorities, " manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Salter, J. T,. "The Anatomy of Freedom, " manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Wartime conditions and Civic Affairs Operations in the Philippines, manuscripts, memoranda, notes, reprints, 1942-1945 (Box 104, Folder 5-6)
  - Subseries 3: Social Science Research
    - Philippine research, manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Review of People and Art of the Philippines, by Gabriel Casal, manuscript, 1982 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - "Philippine Social Structure, " manuscript, correspondence, 1968 (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - A Study in Contrasts, " manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1989 (Box 104, Folder 10-11)
    - "Survey of Anthropological Research in the Philippines and Recommendations for a Future Program, " manuscript, 1946 (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Eggan, Fred, and Roy F. Barton, reprint, 1947 (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - An Analysis of Factors Related to Effective Utilization of Foreign Training, " "Some Missing Variables in Diffusion Research and Innovation, " manuscripts, 1964-1966 (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Chaiken, Miriam S., "Social and Health Consequences of Spontaneous 16Resettlement, " proposal, 1980 (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Congress for Prehistoric Research in the Far East, Manila, notes, programs, clippings, Feburary 13, 1935 (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Conklin, Harold C., "A Bibliography of the Works of Robert B. Fox, " manuscript, reprint, 1986 (Box 104, Folder 17)
    - Cuyugan, R. Santos, "Intellectual Nationalism and the Regional Outlook, " manuscript, 1965 (Box 104, Folder 18)
    - Edgerton, Ronald E., "Dean C. Worcester's Mission among Philippine Upland Tribes, " manuscript, correspondence, 1985 (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - Eslao, Nena, "The Development Cycle of the Filipino Household in an Urban Setting, " manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - Fox, Robert B., "Bibliography of Articles Concerning the Peoples of the Philippines in Primitive Man (1928-1951), " manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 21)
    - Fox, Robert B., "Selected Titles from the Worcester Collection of the Rare Book Room, University of Michigan, " manuscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 22)
    - Guthrie, George M., "Impact of Modernization in the Philippines, " research proposal, undated (Box 104, Folder 23)
    - Harvard University, Peabody Museum, Philippines materials, manuscript, correspondence, 1941 (Box 104, Folder 24)
    - International Rice Research Institute, Los Baños, Laguna, memorandum, 1966 (Box 104, Folder 25)
    - The Philippines from 250, 000 B.C. to1521 A.D.," (Quezon City: Phoenix Publishing House), manuscripts, 1963 (Box 104, Folder 26)
    - Lynch, Frank, manuscript, reprint, 1949, 1955 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Master of Arts and Doctoral dissertations and Masters' theses relating to the Philippines, correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Murphy, Elizabeth D., "The American-Philippine Love-Hate Relationship as Reflected in American and Philippine Literature in English, " manuscript, 1979 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Newberry Library, Philippine materials at, correspondence, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Philippine Studies Newsletter, correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Schlegel, Stuart A., "Religious Syncretism and Reform in a Philippine Moslem Society, " correspondence, research proposal, 1972 (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Scott, William H., "Filipino Class Structure in the 16th Century, " manuscript, 1978 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Social Science Information, 1980 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Essays Presented to Professor H. Otley Beyer, correspondence, outline, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Tubangui, Helen R., "Manila Area Study, " manuscript, reprint, 1962 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - A List of Selected Files, "1942 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - University of Chicago, Committee on Far Eastern Civilizations, Doctoral Dissertations and Masters' Thesis on Asia 1894-1962, 1962 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1925, 1958 (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 4: Miscellaneous
    - Eggan, Fred, and Evett D. Hester, emergency food requirements in the Philippines, reports, 1943 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Hart, Donn V., guides to Philippine magazines, manuscripts, undated (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Hester, Evett D., Philippine settlement patterns and urbanization, notes, maps, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Killings of Robert J. Conklin and Marvin S. Pittman Jr. in Ifugao, Mountain Province, manuscripts, reprints, clippings, 1950 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Social Science Research Council, grant application, 1949 (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, 1921, 1963 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 5: Philippine Newspapers
    - Hart, Donn V., "The Philippines at Syracuse University," Manila Chronicle, September 20, 1966 (Box C)
    - Manila Bulletin, Independence Day Edition, June 12, 1962 (Box C)
    - Manila Chronicle, This Week, April 16, 1950 (Box C)
    - Manila Chronicle, This Week, Philippine towns, 1961 (Box C)
    - Miscellaneous, clippings, 1948-1961 (Box C)
  - Subseries 6: Northern Philippines
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Baguio, clippings, magazines, 1948-1961 (Box 105, Folder 20-21)
      - Free Philippines, newspapers, 1944-1945 (2) (Box 106, Folder 1-2)
      - Mountain Province and Northern Luzon, climate charts, 1940-1946 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - Northern Luzon, maps, undated (Box 106, Folder 4)
      - Maps, correspondence, reprint, 1951-1961 (Box 106, Folder 5)
      - Maps, undated (Box C)